{
    "Linguistics": [
        {
            "value": 100,
            "question": "This language is the most spoken in the world, spoken by 13% of the world's population.",
            "answer": "What is Mandarin?"
        },
        {
            "value": 200,
            "question": "Hawaiians have over 200 different words for this English word for weather.",
            "answer": "What is 'rain'?"
        },
        {
            "value": 300,
            "question": "This English word comes from the first two letters of the Greek Alphabet.",
            "answer": "What is 'alphabet'?"
        },
        {
            "value": 400,
            "question": "This language, spoken in the mountains between France and Spain, has no relation to any other known language.",
            "answer": "What is Basque?"
        },
        {
            "value": 500,
            "question": "The first printed book was in this language.",
            "answer": "What is German?"
        }
    ],
    "In the News": [
        {
            "value": 100,
            "question": "Two dams were breached by swollen rain waters in this state.",
            "answer": "What is Michigan?"
        },
        {
            "value": 200,
            "question": "China announced a plan to impose new security laws on this country.",
            "answer": "What is Hong Kong?"
        },
        {
            "value": 300,
            "question": "A pair of game-worn shoes from this athlete's rookie season sold in an online Sotheby's auction $560,000.",
            "answer": "Who is Michael Jordan?"
        },
        {
            "value": 400,
            "question": "President Trump unveiled that he has been taking this drug to ward off COVID-19.",
            "answer": "What is hydroxychloroquine?"
        },
        {
            "value": 500,
            "question": "An underwater salvage company was granted approval last week to cut into the wreckage of the Titantic to try to recover this item.",
            "answer": "What is a Marconi telegraph used to transmit distress signals?"
        }

    ],
    "American Presidents Named James": [
        {
            "value": 100,
            "question": "This President once commanded a submarine",
            "answer": "Who is Jimmy Carter"
        },
        {
            "value": 200,
            "question": "This President died on a July 4th",
            "answer": "Who is James Monroe?"
        },
        {
            "value": 300,
            "question": "This President was the smallest of American Presidents, with a height of 5'4\" and weighing less than 100 pounds.",
            "answer": "Who is James Madison?"
        },
        {
            "value": 400,
            "question": "This President was the first left-handd President, and could write with both hands simultaneously in two different languages.",
            "answer": "Who is James Garfield?"
        },
        {
            "value": 500,
            "question": "This President never married.",
            "answer": "Who is James Buchanan?"
        }
    ],
    "Famous People with non-James Schaneville/Underwood Names": [
        {
            "value": 100,
            "question": "12th President of the United States",
            "answer": "Who is Zachary Taylor"
        },
        {
            "value": 200,
            "question": "This famous physicist, cosmologist and author had a 'stellar' career despite having an early-onset motor neuron disease.",
            "answer": "Who is Stephen Hawking?"
        },
        {
            "value": 300,
            "question": "This actor is best known for his roles on The Andy Griffith Show and Three's Company.",
            "answer": "Who is Don Knotts?"
        },
        {
            "value": 400,
            "question": "This actress and singer is best known for her role as Kris Monroe in the television series Charlie's Angels.",
            "answer": "Who is Cheryl Ladd?"
        },
        {
            "value": 500,
            "question": "This Czar was the last of Russia under Romanov rule during World War I.",
            "answer": "Who is Czar Nicholas II?"
        }
    ],
    "Science": [
        {
            "value": 100,
            "question": "Name 5 of the 7 simple machines.",
            "answer": "What are lever, pully, wheel and axle, inclined plane, wedge and screw?"
        },
        {
            "value": 200,
            "question": "At this speed a tropical storm turns into a hurricane.",
            "answer": "What is 74 miles per hour?"
        },
        {
            "value": 300,
            "question": "The amount a 150 pound human being would weigh in the center of the earth.",
            "answer": "What is nothing?"
        },
        {
            "value": 400,
            "question": "This blood type is the universal donor type.",
            "answer": "What is O negative?"
        },
        {
            "value": 500,
            "question": "Splitting a laser light into two beams through a silver mirror creates this.",
            "answer": "What is a hologram?"
        }
    ]
}